Guide to the George Harmon Coxe Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- October 1997 Acquisition, 1897-1980; 2; 20.14; (49 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1897-1980
    - Wilhelm Goldman Verlag, 1961-1975 (Box 56)
    - Wilhelm Goldman Verlag - contracts, 1968-1976 (Box 56)
  - Photographs, 1901-1975
    - Unidentified children [1 photograph], undated (Box 57)
    - Unidentified man [3 photographs], 1975, undated (Box 57)
    - Coxe, Elizabeth [6 photographs], undated (Box 57)
    - Coxe, George Harmon [1 photograph], undated (Box 57)
    - Coxe, George Harmon, passport photographs, [4 photographs], 1945 (Box 57)
    - Coxe, George Harmon, as a boy [11 photographs], undated (Box 57)
    - Coxe, George Harmon, with unidentified man, [1 photograph], undated (Box 57)
    - Coxe, George Harmon, with unidentified man, Sans Souci Restaurant Garden, Havana, Cuba, [1 photograph], undated (Box 57)
    - Coxe, George Harmon with Mrs. James Jones, and Mrs. George Harmon Coxe, Sr. [1 photograph], 1954 (Box 57)
    - Coxe, Mrs. George Harmon, with Veronica Parker Johns, and unidentified woman, Mystery Writers Annual Dinner [1 photograph, 2 copies], 1952 (Box 57)
    - Coxe, George Harmon with John Roeburt [ 1 photograph], undated (Box 57)
    - [Coxe, George Harmon, Sr.?] [1 photograph], undated; 3 (Box 57)
    - Pacific Writer's Mission [24 photographs], 1945 (Box 57)
    - President McKinley's funeral train [1 photograph], 1901 (Box 57)
    - Souvenir book of GHC's trip to the Naval Air Station, Norman, OK. With: typescript letter signed to GHC from Lt. Alan R. Jackson, 1943 October 11 (Box 57)
    - Mrs. Kenn Titusville [?], Mrs. Pierce-Jamestown, Mrs. B.F. Cirreus [?], and Harriet [?] [1 photograph], 1896 (Box 57)
    - Unidentified people [5 photographs], 1908, undated (Box 58)
    - Casey Crime Photographer, radio cast, with autographs [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - Cornell University, Class of 1923, reunion [1 photographs], undated (Box 58)
    - Coxe, Elizabeth [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - Coxe, Elizabeth, with George Harmon Coxe III, and Janet Coxe [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon [16 photographs], undated (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon [1 photograph], [no year] June 8 (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon, with "Mattox" and "Kaufman" [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon [11 photographs], 1906-61; 7 (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon and Elizabeth [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon and Elizabeth Coxe, with two unidentified women. [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon and Elizabeth Coxe on board the Christoforo Colombo [1 photograph], circa 1968 (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon III [2 photographs], 1947-1949; 2 (Box 58)
    - Coxe, George Harmon III, and Janet Coxe [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - [Knopf, Alfred?] [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - McIntosh, Hal, George Harmon Coxe drawing [1 photograph], undated (Box 58)
    - Pryor, Laurence [14 photographs], undated; 2 (Box 58)
    - Sigma Nu Fraternity, Cornell University [1 photograph], 1921 (Box 58)
    - Unidentified places [75 photographs], 1970, undated; 5 (Box 58)
    - Unidentified boat [4 photographs], undated (Box 59)
    - Barbados, British Honduras, and Trinidad [38 photographs], undated (Box 59)
    - Casablanca and Europe [55 photographs], undated (Box 59)
    - Coxe House in Old Lyme, CT [20 photographs], undated; 2 (Box 59)
    - [Cuba?] [18 photographs], undated (Box 59)
    - Europe [105 photographs], undated; 5 (Box 59)
    - Football games, undated (Box 59)
    - Lisbon, Portugal [22 photographs], undated (Box 59)
    - Mexico [19 photographs], undated (Box 59)
    - New Orleans, Los Angeles [11 photographs], undated (Box 59)
    - Olean High School [1 photograph], undated (Box 59)
    - St. Vincent, British West Indies [4 photographs], undated (Box 59)
  - Other Papers, 1898-1980
    - Financial Papers
      - Bills, A-Z, 1922-1974 (Box 60)
      - Barclay's Bank Limited, checkbook register, 1956 (Box 60)
      - Club Morgan, checks, 1956 (Box 60)
      - Contracts A-C, 1960-1974 (Box 60)
      - Contracts D-L, 1956-1979 (Box 60)
      - Contracts M-Z, 1936-1979 (Box 60)
      - Copyright assignments, miscellaneous, 1936-1939 (Box 60)
      - A. M. Heath Co., Ltd., royalty statements, 1953-1956; 5 (Box 60)
      - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., royalty statements, 1935-1959; 2 (Box 60)
      - Avon Books and Periodicals, royalty statements, 1947-1951 (Box 61)
      - Gennossenschaftliche Zentral Bank, Zurich, royalty statements, 1961-1979 (Box 61)
      - King Features Syndicate, royalty statements, undated (Box 61)
      - Samuel French, Inc., royalty statements, 1959-1964 (Box 61)
      - Barclay's Bank Limited, statements, 1951-1980 (Box 61)
      - Statements, A-Z, 1939-1978 (Box 61)
      - Gennossenschaftliche Zentral Bank, Zurich, statements, 1961-1963 (Box 61)
      - Gennossenschaftliche Zentral Bank, Basel, statements, 1962-1976 (Box 61)
    - Subject Files
      - Advertising copy - miscellaneous, 1963-1965 (Box 62)
      - Barbados driver's license, 1956 (Box 62)
      - Books by George Harmon Coxe - statistics on number of copies sold, 1956 (Box 62)
      - Crossword puzzle, undated (Box 62)
      - Dance cards, 1898-1899 (Box 62)
      - Department of Police, New Orleans, LA. Table of Organization. With: blank complaint report., 1958 (Box 62)
      - Dixiana Cafe - dinner menu, undated (Box 62)
      - Handy, W. C. Yellow Dog Blues, sheet music, piano arrangement by Herman Chittison. With an inscription to GHC by Herman Chittison., 1955 (Box 62)
      - I Want a Book (Series II No. 28), radio interview with George Harmon Coxe by Meredith Bloss, 1942 (Box 62)
      - The Lady is Afraid, early copies list, undated (Box 62)
      - The Most Famous Detectives of Fiction, cancelled stamps., 1972 (Box 62)
      - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures, identification card issued to George Harmon Coxe, 1944 (Box 62)
      - Mystery Writers Awards, winners, 1969 (Box 62)
      - Nemo-Hygenic Corsetry final exam, 1916 (Box 62)
      - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Co., tickets, 1956 (Box 62)
      - Pacific Writer's Mission, materials relating to GHC's trip to the Pacific, 1945 (Box 62)
      - Pacific Writer's Mission, notes made by GHC, 1945; 2 (Box 62)
      - Pacific Writer's Mission, pass, 1945 (Box 62)
      - Press releases, 1963 (Box 62)
      - Square dances, undated (Box 62)
      - Statement concerning GHC's golf cart accident, 1974 (Box 62)
      - The Use of Lie Detector Technique in Determining Deception., undated (Box 62)
      - War Correspondent's patch [2 patches], 1945 (Box 62)
      - Who's Who - sketch, undated (Box 62)
    - Printed Material
      - Scrapbooks of clippings, undated; 4 (Box 63)
      - Scrapbooks of clippings, undated; 4 (Box 64)
      - Scrapbooks of clippings, undated; 4 (Box 65)
      - The American Magazine. Springfield, Ohio, 1942-1951
        - Vol. CXXXIII, no. 4, 1942 April (Box 66)
        - Vol. CXXXVII, no. 4, 1944 October (Box 66)
        - Vol. CXL, no. 4, 1945 October (Box 66)
        - Vol. CXLV, no. l, 1948 January (Box 66)
        - Vol. CXLVI, no. 3, 1948 September (Box 66)
        - Vol. CLI, no. 3, 1951 March (Box 66)
      - Criminal Investigation. Department of the Army Field Manual FM 19-20. Washington, D.C.: United States Government Printing Office, 1951, 1951 July (Box 66)
      - Detective Story Magazine. New York: 1923, Vol. LVII, no. 2, 1923 April 21 (Box 66)
      - Chamber of Commerce Newsletter. Hilton Head Island, South Carolina: 1966. Vol. 1, no. 9, 1966 February (Box 66)
      - Latin American Report. New Orleans: 1962. Vol. 5, no. 1, 1962 August (Box 66)
      - Uge-Revyen. Danish serial featuring works by George Harmon Coxe, 1948 April - September (Box 66)
      - Unsorted printed material by, about, and relating to George Harmon Coxe, 1930-1965 (Box 66)
      - Newspapers, 1963-1973 (Box 67)
      - Barta Press printed material, circa 1930 (Box 67)
      - Clippings, undated (Box 67)
      - Carribean Land Falls Cruise, information packet, 1970 (Box 67)
      - Information relating to British Honduras, circa 1973 (Box 67)
      - Unsorted printed material by, about, or relating to George Harmon Coxe, circa 1930-80; 10 (Box 68)
      - Clippings, undated; 6 (Box 69)
      - Clippings, undated; 6 (Box 70)
      - Francis Bannerman & Sons military catalog, 1933 (Box 70)
    - Personal Papers and Other Material
      - Original Casey - Black Mask drawings, undated (Box 71)
      - Contracts, 1954-68 (Box 71)
      - Correspondence from publishers, undated; 3 (Box 71)
        Includes typescript carbon of "The Fourth Visitor," with letter from Cosmopolitan magazine, May 7, 1942.
      - Knopf, Shaw Nebel, undated (Box 71)
      - Chandler, Raymond, undated (Box 71)
      - Sanders, Sydney A., undated; 5 (Box 71)
      - National Geographic Society certificate, 1938 (Box 72)
      - Metal bookmarked engraved with "G. H. C.", undated (Box 72)
      - School records of George Harmon Coxe, 1915-1921 (Box 72)
      - Wallet with material related to Coxe as a war correspondent, 1945 (Box 72)
      - Unsorted and unidentified papers, undated; 2 (Box 72)
      - Unsorted and unidentified papers, undated; 28 (Box 73)
        Includes correspondence, writings, photographs, financial papers, and printed material.
      - Unsorted and unidentified papers, undated; 15 (Box 74)
        Includes primarily printed material, with some correspondence.
      - Unsorted and unidentified papers, undated; 16 (Box 75)
        Includes primarily printed material, with some notebooks and correspondence.
      - Envelope, undated (Box 76)
      - Leather folio, undated (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, undated (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Photograph of George Harmon Coxe with unidentfied group, undated (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - The American Boy magazine, undated (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Clippings, undated (Box 78 (Oversize))
  - Restricted Fragile
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted Fragile Material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - Elmira Free Academy papers, undated (Box 79)
    - Unsorted papers, undated; 2 (Box 79)
    - Double or Nothing, published copy, 1936 November (Box 79)
    - The Four Just Men, typescript, undated (Box 79)
    - Murder in Pictures, published copy, undated (Box 79)
    - Two Man Job, undated (Box 79)
    - Letters are Poison, undated (Box 79)
    - Special Assignment, undated (Box 79)
    - Fall Guy, undated (Box 79)
    - Push-Over, undated (Box 79)
    - Women are Trouble, undated (Box 79)
    - Mr. Casey Flashguns Murder, undated (Box 79)
    - Pinch Hitters, undated (Box 79)
    - Thirty Tickets to Win, undated (Box 79)
    - Hot Delivery, undated (Box 79)
    - Earned Reward, undated (Box 79)
    - Too Many Women, undated (Box 79)
    - Buried Evidence, undated (Box 79)
    - Trouble for Two, undated (Box 79)
    - Portrait of Murder, undated (Box 79)
    - Murder Mix-up, undated (Box 79)
    - Casey Detective, undated (Box 79)